满意了吗
Are we done?
不  不  听我说
No, now listen, I, uh--
我连襟遭到攻击的事
This attack on my brother-in-law,
我不  我不明白是什么意思
I don't-- I don't know what it means.
拜托了
Please...
我为我的家人感到担心
I fear for my family.
我保证他们会没事的
I'm sure they'll be fine.
我听说那个幸存的歹徒受了重伤
I am told the assassin that survived is gravely injured.
我想他可能也活不久了
It's doubtful he'll live.
好了  说谢谢然后和我握手
Now thank me and shake my hand.
谢谢你  感激不尽
Uh, thank you. Thank you again.
别客气  怀特先生
You're quite welcome, Mr. White.
出什么事了
What's happening?
8点43分
8:43.
死亡时间  8点43分
Time of death, 20:43.
去地狱吧  你这个人渣
Burn in hell, you piece of shit.
其中一名疑犯枪手当场死亡
One suspected gunman died at the scene.
另一名则在当地医院
The second succumbed to his wounds
伤重不治死亡
earlier this evening at an area hospital.
毒品管制局和联邦调查局
Agents with the DEA and FBI
连同阿尔布开克警局凶案组的探员
in conjunction with APD homicide detectives,
正和墨西哥执法机构一起
are working with Mexico law enforcement
调查此次案件
attempt to identified the suspect
接下来的我给你讲吧
I can give you highlights.
你的侄子们越来越没有耐心了
Your nephews grew impatient.
一直逼我
They continue to press me
让我同意杀掉沃尔特・怀特
for my permission to kill Walter White.
在我拒绝后
When I wouldn't give it,
他们决定取而代之杀掉毒品管制局探员施拉德
they settled instead for DEA agent Schrader.
但在他们动手前
But phone call was placed to Agent Schrader
有人打电话告诉了施拉德探员
moments before the attack,
让他占了先机
thus giving him the upper hand.
马尔科脸上中枪当场死亡
Marco was shot in the face and died instantly.
莱昂内尔勉强支撑几个小时后死亡
Leonel lingered for several hours.
那个打给毒品管制局探员的电话
The warning call to the DEA agent--
胡安・波萨可能知道
Juan Bolsa may have some insight
是谁打的
into who placed it.
但昨天  墨西哥联邦军队冲入他家
But yesterday, the federales were at his hacienda,
混乱中  他中枪死亡
and in the confusion, Juan was shot dead.
可能是意外吧
An accident, perhaps.
没准是他手下干的
A mistake made by his own men,
只有天知道了
though we may never know.
无论如何  我觉得应该由我来告诉我
At any rate, I thought you should hear from me.
这就叫血债血偿  赫克托
This is what comes of blood for blood, Hector.
血债血偿[西语]
Sangre por sangre.
第四季 第八集
S04E08: Hermanos
这是很吵的那个吗
So is this the loud one?
什么
What?
我总记不住名字
I can never remember.
这是那个很吵带磁性的机器吗
Is this the loud machine with the magnets?
不  这是个电脑断层扫描
No. This is the PET/CT scan.
正子断层扫描
Positron emission tomography.
他们是和
They pair that with
X光计算机断层扫描一起做的
the computed X-ray tomography.
很安静  没有磁性
Quiet. No magnets.
是吗  好吧
Right. Okay.
谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
我对这还不太熟
I'm still pretty new at this.
我才刚刚开始新的事业
I mean, one minute I'm starting a new business.
还准备和老婆一起要个孩子
My wife and I are thinking about having kids.
来医院做了个检查  结果就
Walk into a doctor's office, and suddenly, boom--
-我所理解的人生  -抱歉  稍等
- Life as I know it - Excuse me.
对  我还等着听
Yes. I'm-- I'm waiting to hear a progress report
那件事的进度报告呢
on that thing we discussed.
给我回电话
So call me.
所以对我来说  这个大打击一下敲醒了我
Anyway, so for me, that's been the biggest wake-up call--
放开手  听天由命吧
letting go, giving up control.
老话说的好
It's like they say--
人算不如天算
you know, man plans, and God laughs.
简直扯淡
That is such bullshit.
什么
Excuse me?
不要放弃控制
Never give up control.
命运就掌握在你自己手中
Live life on your own terms.
我明白你的意思
Yeah. No. I get what you're saying.
但这可是癌症
But-- But, uh, cancer's cancer, so--
去他妈的癌症
Oh, to hell with your cancer.
癌症这段时间可是我人生中最美好的时候
I've been living with cancer for the better part of a year.
一开始  他们都说
Right from the start, it's a death sentence.
我被判了死刑
It's what they keep telling me.
但是你知道吗
Well, guess what.
人生下来就是要死的
Every life comes with a death sentence.
每过几个月  我都来做定期扫描
So every few months, I come in here for my regular scan,
明知道随时有可能
knowing full well that one of these times--
没准就是今天
hell, maybe even today--
我会听到坏消息
I'm going to hear some bad news.
但在那之前  我的命掌握在谁手中
But until then, who's in charge?
我自己
Me.
这就是我的人生
That's how I live my life.
如果你用制冷机的水
This residue here is why we descale
而不是水管的水除垢
with cool water from the walk-in
就不会留有这些残渣  记住了吗
and not water from the tap, remember?
-嗯  -请再洗一遍
- Yeah. - Do it again, please.
更多美味更多欢笑就在洛博罗炸鸡馆  你好
Pollos Hermanos, where something delicious is always cooking.
好的  探员
Yes, detective.
古斯塔沃  多谢你过来
Gustavo, thanks for coming in.
我的荣幸  基思怎么样了
My pleasure. How's Kathi?
好多了  谢谢你
Much better, thank you.
这位你应该认识  汉克・施拉德
And you know Hank Schrader.
是的  没错
Ah, yes, indeed.
还有史蒂芬・戈麦斯
And Steve Gomez.
吃得还满意吗
How was your meal?
前几天我和施拉德探员
Agent Schrader and I had a chance
在我其中一间餐厅碰过面
to catch up in one of my restaurants a few days ago.
如果不是怕肥得过不了门
I'd eat there every day,
我愿意每天都吃那个
but I wouldn't fit through the door.
-可以开始了吗  -当然
- Well, should we get started? - Yeah.
不介意的话
I'd like to record this conversation,
-这段对话我要录音  -没问题
- if that's okay. - Of course.
毒品管制局和我们
The DEA is working on an investigation
正在共同调查一起案件
which may overlap with my own,
所以今天才请他过来
so I've asked them to sit in with us today.
古斯  我们很感谢你
Gus, we all appreciate
愿意过来和我们谈
your coming in here to talk to us,
但你也有权让你的律师在场
but you have the right to have an attorney present also.
我觉得应该不需要吧
Oh, well, I can't see how that would be necessary.
但我不知道你们为什么找我
But then again I have no idea why I'm here.
那我们继续吧
So you wish to continue?
请  我很想知道原因
Please. I'm very anxious to find out what this is all about.
我们在一个宗罪案现场发现了你的指纹
Sir, your fingerprints were found at a crime scene.
真的吗
Really?
不可思议
That's surprising.
是起和毒品有关的谋杀案
A drug-related homicide.
盖尔・伯蒂彻的公寓吧
Gale Boetticher's apartment.
所以你认识被害人
So you knew the victim.
15年前  我捐助了新墨西哥大学化学奖学金
15 years ago, I established a chemistry scholarship at UNM.
用马克西米诺・阿辛尼耶格的名字命名
I named it after Maximino Arsiniega,
一个我英年早逝的朋友
a dear friend of mine who died too young.
盖尔获得了奖学金
Gale was a recipient of this scholarship.
他应该是获得奖学金的众多人之一
He was, uh, perhaps one of three dozen.
我知道了
I see.
伯蒂彻先生毕业于
And Mr. Boetticher graduated in...
1999年
1999.
应该没错
That sounds right.
你和他一直都保持联系吗
And you kept in regular contact with him over all this time?
没有  我很多年没见过他了
Oh, no. I hadn't seen Gale for years
直到几个星期前偶然碰到他
until I ran into him a few weeks ago.
在哪碰到的
Ran into him where?
在餐厅
At the restaurant.
说"偶遇"可能有点不太恰当
Uh, well, "Ran into" Isn't quite accurate,
我觉得他是特地来找我的
as I assume he came by to re-establish contact with me.
我们聊了一下
We caught up briefly.
他邀请我第二天晚上一起吃饭
He invited me to dinner the following night,
我答应了
and I accepted.
大概一周后
It was, uh, perhaps a week later
我才在报纸上看到他的消息
I read about him in the paper.
你说是和毒品有关
Drug related, you said?
很有可能
It's a good possibility.
报纸没有提到这一点
The paper made no mention of that.
我还以为是普通谋杀
I assumed that it was a random crime.
他几年都和你没有联系
So after years with no contact,
突然出现在你的餐厅
he shows up in your restaurant,
和你叙叙旧
remakes your acquaintance,
然后邀请你吃晚饭
and invites you to dinner?
是的  因为他需要钱
Yeah, he wanted money.
盖尔・伯蒂彻找你借钱
Gale Boetticher asked you for money?
他没有直说
He didn't come right out and say that.
只是含糊其辞的说
He spoke in terms
有一个投资的好机会
of a vague investment opportunity,
但我认识他只是想借钱
but it was my suspicion, yes,
因为他邀请我去他家
as to why he invited me into his home.
他是个很有才华的化学家
He was a very talented chemist,
虽然很有可能创出一番事业
but for reasons I never understood,
但基于某种我不知道的原因
he was more interested in taking shortcuts
他总是想走捷径
than what would or could have been a very promising career.
即使有这样的毛病
But personal shortcomings notwithstanding,
但他仍是个热情  温和的人
he was a warm, gentle person,
我很想念他
and I thought a lot of him.
无论如何
At any rate, I, uh,
我拒绝了他的要求
declined his business offer,
吃晚饭之后我就离开了
and, after what was a very pleasant meal, left.
能告诉我们
Can you tell us where you were
23号星期3晚上8点左右
on the night of Wednesday the 23rd
你在哪里吗
at around 8 P.M.?
不是指责  只是问一下
Not an accusation, just a question.
我明白  等我想一下
Oh, I understand. Let's see.
23号
23rd.
7点到10点的时候
I was at a fundraiser at Presbyterian Hospital.
我在长老会医院出席一个筹款活动
I was there from 7 to about 10.
还有谁有问题
Anyone else?
嗯  对不起  我有
Uh, sorry, yeah.
只是  还有一件事
Just, uh, just one other thing.
古斯塔沃・福林是你的真名吗
Uh, is Gustavo Fring your real name?
是不是我的真名
Is it my real name?
我知道你生于智利
I know you're a Chilean national,
可是那里完全没有你生活过的记录
but there are no records of you ever living there.
真的吗
Really?
我是说  记录显示
I mean, records show
你在1986年移民墨西哥
that you immigrated to Mexico in 1986,
几年后
and then, a couple of years later,
你获得了美国的入境签证
you were granted an entry visa to the United States.
可是完全没有古斯塔沃・福林
But there's no record of Gustavo Fring
曾经在智利生活的记录
ever having existed in Chile,
这让我觉得很奇怪
which I find-- I don't know-- uh, strange.
其实  一点都不奇怪
Well, really, it isn't.
皮诺切特将军的军政府犯下了很多罪行
General Pinochet's government was guilty of a great many sins.
侵犯人权是其中最大最重的罪行
First and foremost were his human rights abuses.
但是保管文件记录也是极为不可靠
But it was also notoriously unreliable at keeping records.
我敢肯定  只要你继续挖下去  肯定能发现
I'm sure, if you keep digging, you'll find me.
好的  我觉得这就够了  古斯
Okay. I think that's it, Gus.
谢谢你
Uh, thank you.
希望我能起到一些作用
I hope that I was of some small help.
当然了  谢谢你
You were, absolutely. Thank you.
不客气
You're very welcome.
很高兴再次见到您
Good to see you again.
不  不用起身  谢谢你
Oh, no. No, please, please. Thank you.
谢谢
Thanks.
先生们  告辞
Gentlemen.
我们应该相信么
So, are we buying?
对他名字的问题
This thing with his name--
你觉得智利那边究竟什么问题
what are you thinking there?
当然了  南美那边的记录保存可能是有问题
Sure, the record keeping in South America is hit or miss.
我们也一直遇上这种情况  对不对
I mean, we run into that all the time, right?
但我们总能发现点什么的
We usually find something.
我看  这人在86年之前简直是个幽灵
I mean, before '86, this guy's a ghost.
要是国务院对他的背景不满意
If the State Department wasn't satisfied with his records,
他们不会接受他入籍的
they wouldn't have naturalized him.
有可能
Well, maybe,
可他是89年从墨西哥移民过来的
but he immigrated from Mexico in '89.
那时候国务院的背景调查
You know, the state just wasn't as tough
不像911之后那么严格
on background checks pre-9/11.
就算这样  我也没看出
Regardless, I don't know what this has to do
这和手上的案子有什么关系
with the case at hand.
当然  我也很好奇
I was definitely curious
为什么他的指纹会出现在伯蒂彻的公寓里
when his prints show up at Boetticher's apartment,
但是  我觉得奖学金的说法说得通
but for me, the scholarship thing explains it.
我承认我有一定的偏袒
Well, I'll admit to a certain degree of bias.
这人长期以来一直是毒品管制局的忠实伙伴
This man has been a longtime friend of DEA,
可是  嗯
but that being said, uh...
我觉得他的故事是可信的
I thought his story was credible.
我同意  这故事的确不错
Well, I agree. I think it was a good story.
可是  为什么我们现在才听说
Still, why are we hearing it now?
什么意思
What do you mean?
如你所说
Well, like you said, he's a--
这人是执法部门的好伙伴
this man's a big law enforcement booster.
有一天他在报上读到了
One day he's reading a newspaper
一个刚与他共进晚餐的人的死讯
and sees that somebody he just had dinner with,
这个人他经常想起
somebody he thought a lot of, was murdered.
他读到这段新闻  怎么不打个电话来
He reads this, and he doesn't make a phone call?
没打给你  也没打给其他那些警察朋友们
Doesn't call you or one of his other cop friends
来谈谈他和本案的联系
to share his connection with the case
或者是问问本案的调查进展
or ask about the investigation.
我们不能光凭一个人没打来电话
We can't predicate a criminal investigation
就对他展开调查
on a person not making phone calls.
那你怎么想  提姆
What do you think, Tim?
我想跟进奖学金和不在场证明这两条线
Well, I want to follow up on the scholarship, the alibi.
但是总体来说  我相信他说的
But my overall impression? I believed him.
鸟池做的很不错
Nice touch. Bird bath.
小伙子  过得怎么样
Hey, tiger. How's it hanging?
很好
Good.
房子很不错
Yeah. So, very nice.
房租多少
What's the damage?
1200美金一个月
1,200 a month.
我仔细调查了周围的社区环境
I did a lot of researching for this neighborhood.
挺划算的
It's a pretty good deal.
开玩笑呢  简直是超划算啊
You kidding me? That's a great deal.
说到这个
Uh, speaking of which, ahem.
这是这周的
That's for the week,
考虑到搬家可能遇到的麻烦
plus there's a little extra in there
还稍微多加了一些
for any move-related incidentals.
谢谢
Thank you.
小伙子  新学校怎么样
Hey, champ, how's the new school?
不错
Good.
我在你那个年纪时很喜欢学校
I loved school when I was your age.
跷跷板  故事时间
Seesaws, story time,
拿着棒子追小姑娘
chasing girls with sticks.
直到五年级
It wasn't until the fifth grade
我才发现她也喜欢我
that I found out she liked me, too.
可那时她家已经搬到斯克代尔去了
But by then her family had moved to Scottsdale,
所以就
so...
及时行乐  记住了么
carpe diem, okay?
好的
Okay.
好小子  哈
All right, good boy. Ha!
请你再替我们俩感谢一下杰西
So, um, you'll thank Jesse again from both of us.
没问题
You got it.
他现在怎么样了
So is he-- How's he doing?
杰西
Jesse?
他很好
He's good.
他很忙
He's, uh... he's busy.
房子怎么样
How is it?
空间很大  灯很多
Oh, there's space, lots of light.
后面还带个小花园  很不错
It's-- A little garden out back. It's nice.
布鲁克他怎样
And Brock? How's he doing?
听着  每周都这样像艾德・麦克马洪
Hey, look, I don't mind dropping checks off
一样扔下支票就走  我真的是一点都不介意
every week like Ed McMahon.
可是如果你真的想知道他们怎样了
But if you really want to know how they're doing,
为什么不自己去看看
why don't you go see for yourself?
我等下来找你们
I'll catch you later.
要不要我送你回家
Hey, you going to need a ride home?
不用
No.
真棒
Great.
不管怎样  我很自豪我没有失去冷静
Anyway, I'm proud for not losing my cool.
另外我还向洗车员工表现了
Plus it shows our wipe-down crew
若是顾客太过粗鲁
that I will support them
我是会支持他们的
if a customer is being really rude to them.
你对洗车店老板这个角色还真是投入啊
You're really taking to this whole be your own boss thing.
是啊  是有点
Yeah. I guess I am.
实际上
Actually,
我正打算升职到管理层
I'm thinking about making a move up to management.
-嗯  -老天啊
- Mmm. - Ah, Jesus.
美国公司们小心了
Corporate America, look out.
真对不起了
Oh, excuse me.
这将是我的一次重大提升
I would be a vast improvement.
克莱曼医院没有一个管理部分的人
No one in Kleinman's entire front office
知道做X光检查应该先做什么
knows the first thing about giving an X-ray,
但这只是
which just-- ahh.
爸爸  扫描的结果怎么样
Hey, Dad, uh, whatever happened with your scan?
报告拿回来了吗
Did-- Did you get the results back?
是啊  拿回来了
Yeah. I did.
我的症状仍在减轻中
And I'm still in remission.
所以你们还得忍我一阵子了
So you're all going to have to be stuck with me for a while longer.
恭喜了  伙计
Cheers, buddy.
你怎么样了  汉克
What about you, Hank?
这几天感觉怎么样
How you feeling these days?
不错  越来越好了
Well, I'm getting there.
前两天  他又和毒品管制局那帮人
The other day, he had a big powwow
聚在一起捣鬼了
with all the DEA muckity-mucks.
出什么事了
What was that about?
没什么  又是一条死胡同
Nothing. Just a dead end.
他也不肯跟我说
He won't tell me, either.
显然  这属于绝密级别
Apparently, it's all very hush-hush.
沃尔特  能帮我个忙吗
Hey, Walt, can you do me a favor?
玛丽明天要工作
Uh, Marie's working tomorrow,
而明天市集那边
and there's this gem and mineral show
有个宝矿石展览
that's opening at the fairgrounds.
能不能请你送我去
I wondered if you can maybe give me a lift.
当然了
Yeah. Sure.
高中时我也收集过矿石
I had a collection of my own back in high school.
没什么特别值钱的
I mean, nothing fancy.
只是入门级别的绿玉石和石榴石
Just entry-level beryls and garnets,
一块还可以的黑色电气石
one passable black tourmaline.
-这里右拐  -好的
- Turn right here. - Okay.
但是我有一块铯绿柱石
But I did have one piece of morganite
非常特别
that was very special.
它曾经被加热过
It had been heat treated,
所有有那种经典的反光效果
so it had that classic cast to it,
那种玫瑰色  近乎鲑鱼肉色  知道吗
that rose, almost salmon hue, you know?
喂  沃尔特  根本没有什么矿石展  懂么
Hey, Walt, there's no rock show, okay?
我只是不想吓到玛丽
I just said that so Marie wouldn't freak.
这里右拐
Take a right here.
有什么吓人的
Freak about what?
汉克  我们去哪里
Hank, where are we going?
你饿了?
You hungry?
我们不是来买炸鸡的
We're not here for the chicken.
关掉引擎
Kill the engine.
好了  呵呵呵
All right, heh heh heh.
准备来点刺激的了么
You ready for your mind to be blown?
当然了
Uh, sure.
古斯塔沃・福林
Gustavo Fring.
记得他么
Remember him?
枪击案发生后他来过医院
He came down to the hospital after the shooting
跑来劳军的
and put up the reward?
他每年都赞助毒品管制局的募捐长跑
He-- He-- He sponsors the DEA Fun Run every year.
你见过他的
You-- You've met him.
对  募捐长跑那个人
Yeah, the-- the Fun Run guy.
对  对  那个人
Yeah, that-- that guy--
是啊  他怎么了
Yeah. What about him?
我怀疑
Well, I suspect--
尽管无法证明  但是我怀疑
and I can't prove it, mind you, but I suspect...
这人是个大毒枭
the man's a drug dealer.
是啊  卖甲基苯丙胺的
Yeah. Methamphetamine.
说实话  我真心认为
I mean, honest to God, I really believe
这人或许是西南部最大的毒枭之一
that this guy's maybe one of the biggest movers in the southwest.
还记得盖尔・伯蒂彻么
Remember Gale Boetticher?
卡拉OK录像带上那个傻瓜
The, uh, that sad sack from the karaoke video tape?
对
Yeah.
你还说  那人的水平并不令你感到吃惊
And you said that he didn't strike you
是当头儿的类型
as being the boss-man type,
很可能背后还有条大鱼
that probably there was a much bigger guy out there, right?
汉克  那
Hank, that was--
那只是推测
that was just speculation.
没关系  它让我留心调查此事
Doesn't matter. It made me keep at it.
猜我发现了什么
And guess what I find.
伯蒂彻被杀现场
Chicken man's fingerprints
发现了炸鸡店老板的指纹
at Boetticher's murder scene.
于是我们把他叫来问话
So we bring him in--
你认为  古斯塔沃・福林杀了盖尔・伯蒂彻
You think that-- that Gustavo Fring killed Gale Boetticher?
也许不是
Well, probably not.
我是说  他们这些人
I mean, these guys use, you know,
都会让手下动手
like, a dunce to pull the trigger, right?
但是他的现场指纹
But his fingerprints being there was enough
已足够我们找他问话了
for us to bring him in.
你把他带到警局去了
So I-- So you brought him in to the police?
是啊  他坐下跟我们对话
Right. He sits down to talk with us.
问题是他...
The problem is that he--
你问他什么了  他说了什么
What did you ask him? What did he say?
你能让我把话说完吗
Walt, will you let me finish my story here?
抱歉  我只是很感兴趣
Sorry. I'm just, uh, interested.
-如此而已  -明白
- You know. - Yeah, all right.
我们请他过来
So we bring him in,
他对答如流
and he proceeds to kick our asses, okay?
他解释了指纹的事
He's got an explanation for the fingerprints, right?
也有盖尔被杀当晚的不在场证明
He's got an alibi for Gale's murder.
他理由充足得很
I mean, he's got reasons for everything.
这家伙简直比《母女情深》还有说服力
This guy is Terms of Endearment convincing.
80年代美国热映亲情片
那他是清白的
So he's not guilty?
就目前毒品管制局和警方看来
Well, as far as DEA and APD are concerned,
他还没有脱离嫌疑
he's not.
但他还没有正式成为嫌疑人
Officially, Fring's not a suspect.
但是我给你讲
But I'm telling you,
我的直觉告诉我他就是我要找的人
something deep down says he's my guy.
只是仍需证据
Just got to prove it.
汉克  你为何跟我说这个
Hank, why-- why are you telling me this?
我需要帮忙
I need a favor.
帮什么忙
What favor?
看见那辆沃尔沃休旅车了吗
See that Volvo station wagon over there?
那家伙开了一辆十年前的沃尔沃旧款
I mean, the guy drives a 10-year-old Volvo.
真聪明  总之
It's brilliant. Anyway, listen.
我需要你帮我
What I need for you to do...
把这个安在上面
stick this on it.
定位跟踪装置
GPS tracker.
妻子总是怀疑丈夫在外面鬼混
You know, wifey thinks hubby's screwing around on her,
就会想要查清楚
but she wants to be sure. Hmm.
你把这个安在车上
You stick this on the car.
这里看见了吗  是块磁铁
This part right here? It's a magnet.
然后就能知道他的去向
And see where he goes.
太绝了  对吧
Cool, huh?
天空购网上买的  289块
289 from SkyMall.
可惜的是  这不是实时的
Unfortunately, it's not live use,
我们之后还得回来
so we got to come back later and, you know,
把它取下来  插进电脑里看
take it off and stick it in the computer.
不过这已经很先进了
Still, pretty amazing times we live in here.
汉克  这不是违法的吗
Hank, isn't that illegal?
这算不算非法调查...
I mean, isn't there some sort of unlawful search and--
这叫做法外调查
That's, uh, known as extra-legal,
但是相信我吧  你知我知
but trust me. It's our little secret.
很容易的  好吗  你这么办
Look, it's easy, okay? Here's what you do.
把鞋带解开
You untie your shoelace,
朝餐厅走去
then you head toward the restaurant.
经过那辆车的时候
As you're walking past the car,
你低头一看  "该死  鞋带松了"
you look down-- "Oh, hey, darn, my shoe's untied."
好吗
Okay?
接着  趁你
Now, when you-- when you--
弯下腰系鞋带之时
when you bend down to tie your shoe,
就把这个塞进轮胎的轮窝里
you, uh, you stick this up into the wheel well.
然后你就大方走进去  买点什么
Then you go inside and, I don't know--
汉克  我不...
Hank, I-- I don't--
我觉得这事不太靠谱
I don't feel good about this at all.
沃特  我知道
Look, Walt, I-- I-- I know
这种事超出你平常所为
that this sort of thing is outside your comfort zone--
不  我是说这是错误的
No. I mean this is a mistake.
沃特  我需要你帮我  好吗
Walt, I need you to help me out here, okay?
这对我真的很重要
I mean, this is really important to me.
天啊  你要我哀求你吗
Jesus, just-- You make me beg you?
就把它塞进去就行了
Come on, just stick it in there.
好吧
Yeah.
自然一点
Just act normal.
需要点餐吗
May I help you?
我  我
I-- I--
先生  需要点餐吗
Sir, may I help you?
瞧
Look, I--
我没那么做
I didn't do it.
看见了吗  我没下手
See? I didn't do it.
做
Do it.
下手
您需要点餐吗
May I help you with your order?
我
I, uh--
他究竟在干嘛
What the hell is he--
确保它塞牢了
Just, uh, made sure it was secure.
我的汽水呢
Where's my soda?
开玩笑的
Just kidding.
我们走吧
Let's-- Let's go.
瞧  我
Look, I--
我向天发誓  我本以为是要载他
I swear to God I thought I was driving the man
去看矿藏展
to a gem and mineral show.
可他突然让我转向去了你的餐馆
And all of a sudden he has me pulling into your restaurant
告诉我  他在调查你
and-- and-- and telling me that he's investigating you.
虽然你我之间有小摩擦
Look, you and I, we've had our differences,
但我绝不会...
but I would never--
我妹夫
Look, m-my brother-in-law,
显然没有任何证据
evidence-wise, has nothing.
他只是臆测而为
He's-- He's operating on pure conjecture,
每个人  和他共事的所有人
and no one-- not one person that he works with--
都认为你只是
thinks that you are anyone
一家快餐连锁的业主而已
other than an owner of a fast food chain.
但如果汉克遭遇不测
But if something were to happen to Hank,
那只会引来他们对你的注意
then that would only draw their attention to you
也会让我成为目标
and therefore to me as well.
因此我们都有不用武力解决的需要
So we have a mutual interest in resolving this without violence.
我可以确保他一无所获
I will make sure that he discovers nothing.
杰西
Jesse!
怎么了
What?
对  都不等我请你进来
All right. Don't wait to be, like, invited.
家里还有人吗
Are we alone?
进行到哪一步了
So where do we stand?
什么到哪一步了
Where do we stand on what?
我们的计划到哪一步了
Where do we stand with the thing?
你本该实施的计划
The thing that you were supposed to do.
我猜你没去做
I assume you haven't done it.
你不是丢了  对吧
You didn't lose it, did you?
你要是丢了会告诉我的  对吧
You would tell me if you lost it, right?
杰西
Oh, Jesus.
混蛋
Asshole.
你这么上赶  你自己去做吧
You creaming to get it done? Go do it yourself.
要是他没发现我...
If he didn't see me coming like he's some kind of--
算了
This-- All right, look.
我们得抓紧时间了
Our timetable has advanced.
你得这周就安排好会面
You have got to make this meeting happen
明天  有可能的话  今晚
this week, tomorrow-- tonight, if possible.
今晚  真行
Oh. Tonight. Wow.
你这是嗑药了吗
What are you, high?
我妹夫
My brother-in-law--
我那个当毒品管制局探员的妹夫
My DEA agent brother-in-law--
他查到古斯了
He's on to Gus.
你听见我说什么了吗
Did you hear what I just said?
我妹夫在查古斯
My brother-in-law is on to Gus.
是啊是啊  我听见了
Ah, yeah, yeah, I got it.
你妹夫对吧  我在考虑呢
Your brother-in-law, okay? I'm thinking.
这
Look, uh,
要是这就像是在做数学题  代数题呢
so what if this is like math or algebra?
一个正麻烦  加一个负麻烦
You add a plus douche bag to a minus douche bag
等于麻烦归零
and you get, like, zero douche bags.
我来教你怎么做数学
I've got some math for you.
汉克抓到古斯  等于汉克抓到我们
Hank catching Gus equals Hank catching us.
汉克这人
Hank-- Geez.
不屈不挠的
He's relentless, all right?
他不会放弃的
He won't quit.
好吧  我要说的是  他什么也查不到
Yeah, well, he's got nothing is all I can say.
你怎么会知道
Oh, and how would you know that?
因为他在明处
Because he's still above ground.
你觉得像古斯这样的人  会让人
You think a dude like Gus would let your boy
轻易查到他吗
anywhere near him?
他会用他的工具刀好好对付那个残废
He'll break out his box cutter on his sorry gimp ass.
那次晚餐之后  你再也没有见过他吗
So you haven't even seen him since that time at the diner.
好了  不说了
Okay. Shh.
好好想想  好吧
Think. All right.
他们会知道我们交谈过
Um, they've got to be figuring that we've talked,
所以你要告诉麦克
so you need to tell Mike
你很担心汉克的追查
that you are worried about Hank's investigation.
另外汉克已经知道到你的身份了
Okay? Hank already knows who you are, by the way.
再说  你是杀了盖尔的真凶
And besides, you actually did kill Gale,
所以就以此为由
so there's that.
这是你要求与古斯面谈的
This is all good fodder
最好的借口
for you to request a sit-down with Gus
说你要讨论一下  万一汉克找你去问话
so you can discuss what you would say
你该怎么回答
in case Hank brings you in for questioning.
好吗  现在你
Okay? Now you just--
你就说你想
you just say that you want to be--
不  说你需要
no, that-- that you need
对好口供
to be able to be properly coached,
等你接近他
and when you're near him--
你就用这个
you put this to use.
他只会告诉我
He's just going to tell me
要是被抓  就把嘴闭紧
to shut my mouth if I get busted.
他不会安排会面的
He ain't going to set up no meeting.
那你就坚持要求  该死
Well, then insist on it, damn it!
表现得很慌张
Act panicked.
古斯现在坐如针毡
Gus' ass is on the line,
相信我  如果你觉得你牵连其中
And trust me. He will meet with you
他会跟你见面的
if he thinks that you're a liability.
不  他如果觉得我牵连其中
No, he will waste me
他只会杀了我
if he thinks I'm a liability.
无所谓了  伙计
You know what? Whatever, man.
我要去撒尿
I'm going to take a piss.
见面取消 出了点事 老板很忙
你刚才有电话
Uh, I think you got a phone call.
有什么要紧事吗
Anything important?
你好
Yes?
我探了探风声
I did some digging around.
如何
And?
毒品管制局和警方
Neither the DEA nor the APD
都没有把你列为怀疑对象
considers you a person of interest.
施拉德在擅自调查你
Schrader's looking into you totally on his lonesome.
孤立无援
A voice in the wilderness.
有人力物力吗
Does he have resources?
就他自己和他的信用卡
Just him, his credit card,
还有他的司机沃尔特
and his chauffeur Walter.
据传闻  如果他再向默克特提起你
From what I hear, he would be committing career suicide
他的饭碗就保不住了
if he were to mention you to Merkert again.
所以说他没有在我车上安追踪器的令
So no warrant for the tracking device on my car.
对  他太特立独行了
No. The guy's gone totally maverick.
他是妙女神探
He's Miss Daisy with binoculars.
我们处处小心  别被他抓到马脚
We watch our backs, make sure we don't throw him any bones,
他就无机可趁了
he'll never make a case.
那智利的事呢
What about Chile?
连我都查不到你1989年前的资料
If I can't find any trace of you before '89,
施拉德就更难找到了
I seriously doubt Schrader can.
我看更让人头疼的是卡特尔集团
Seems to me the bigger problem's the cartel.
如果他挖掘不到进一步的信息  我们就能应付
We can handle them if that's all we've got on our plate.
不过同时应付施拉德
But dealing with both Schrader
和那帮墨西哥人
and the Mexicans at the same time,
如果他们采取行动时  他正在监视
if he happens to be watching when they make a move,
那事态就不可控制了
they could be the perfect storm.
谢谢
Thank you.
保持联系
I'll be in touch.
你好  赫克托
Hello, Hector.
卡特尔集团给我下了最后通牒
The cartel has given me its ultimatum,
不过我拒绝了
to which I've said no.
毒品管制局的探员施拉德
DEA agent Schrader--
他是个大麻烦
uh, he's a concern.
他在查我的老底
He's looking into my past.
是今天吗  赫克托
Is today the day, Hector?
-古斯塔沃  坐下  你搞得我好紧张  -好
这计划很好  相信好
一切都会顺利的
你疯了吗
老大会把你的蛋给割了
怎么  你要打小报告吗
你们呢
他们是不会说的
他们喜欢这样
你不给我们的客人倒点喝的吗
谁说他们是客人
老板让他们喝
他们才能喝
那么  炸鸡兄弟
我喜欢你们的餐馆
-很高兴你能喜欢  谢谢  -谢谢
黑皮肤和白皮肤
我看不像兄弟
终于见面了
主厨们
你们俩
你们烹制的鸡肉
我发誓  一定是全墨西哥最好吃的鸡肉
谢谢  爱兰迪奥先生
非常荣幸
麦克斯是主厨
全是他的功劳
古斯塔沃太谦虚了
没有他  这餐馆根本开不了
不管你们怎么做到的  继续加油
你们的鸡肉  很带劲
很辛辣
不过不像墨西哥的风味
这是从智利学来的食谱
为了迎合墨西哥人的口味  我们稍作了修改
我打赌  我们比你们智利人更喜欢智利口味
我们墨西哥人喜欢重口味
那么  如果你的搭档负责烹饪
那你又是干什么的
别告诉我你只是个美食家
我负责商业运作
古斯塔沃是个很出色的商人
他是个商人啊
很好  很好
告诉我
那鸡肉  那么好吃
无与伦比
除了那个  你们的菜单里还加了什么
我们有几道配餐
米饭
豆子
如果我们在市场上看到新鲜牛肉
有时我们会准备些墨西哥特制牛肉
还有吗
坦白说吧
你们就没别的了吗  有点味道的其它东西
其它辅料
因为我的手下去你们餐馆
带回来的可不止鸡肉
他们带回了毒品
你们贩毒给他们
冰毒
恕我冒犯  爱兰迪奥先生
我没贩毒给他们
我给的是样品
样品
生意人
我把样品给他们  让他们转交给你
让你看看我们的货
爱兰迪奥先生  古斯塔沃没想冒犯你
可他...  那话的意思是...
我们没别的办法吸引你的注意
我们想和你合作  爱兰迪奥先生
我对冰毒了解得一清二楚
那是穷人的可卡因
只有低收入的人才吸那个
这没赚头
爱兰迪奥先生  我插几句...
我是个受过专业培训的生化学家
我们制造的冰毒
要比你所说的穷人所知道的更高级
这是晶体  像玻璃一样
纯度更高
还有分子的偏光力
分子的结构  是不同的
药效要强得多
这货很有前景
能够让你的利润乘上三倍
或许能上四倍
他们不只是出色的厨师
还很擅长铲肥料
不  不  继续  继续
现在  你几乎只卖可卡因
可古柯植物无法在墨西哥生长
你无非是个中间商
卖方还是哥伦比亚人
他们扣掉走私的利润
尽管你一直在铤而走险
可巨额利润还是他们的
这个新的晶体冰毒
效力更强  比可卡因更容易上瘾
这样就会有更大的需求量
最重要的是  这完全是人工制造的
我们可以给你看制造过程  就在墨西哥
而你能获得全部的利润
我手下很喜欢你们的产品
赫克托  你怎么回事
怎么不给客人拿杯子
你们继续
你们太有才了
我打赌你们是从妈妈那里学来的厨艺  对吗
可化学呢
是我在智利的圣地亚哥大学学的
古斯塔沃为我付的学费
是吗
我有生化学和化学工程的双学位
用最小的资本投资
我们能为你建造工厂级的实验室
培训你的手下制造大量的
高纯度冰毒
真不错
但告诉我一件事
如果你是厨子
我还要他干什么
我不懂
你
为什么我要和一个对我不敬的人谈判
未经我的允许  在我眼皮底下贩毒
还设局让我来见面
就在我手下的面前
我要你干什么
爱兰迪奥先生  求你了
我什么都没卖
如果因为我争取了这次见面
而冒犯了你  我道歉
我很少采取主动
我没有侮辱你的意思
爱兰迪奥先生  古斯塔沃没想冒犯你
我对古斯塔沃的了解如同对兄弟一样
他是个可敬的人
是我认识的最忠诚的人
他把我从圣地亚哥的贫民窟解救出来
是他成就了今天的我
古斯塔沃是个天才  他能让你家财万贯
请打心眼里原谅他这小错误吧
求你了
他是我的搭档
我需要他
我对天发誓
看着他
是你害的
给我听着
你活着  而他死了的唯一原因
就是因为我知道你的底细
可你要清楚
你已经不在智利了
我建议
专心做你的炸鸡
看着我  赫克托
Look at me, Hector.
看着我
Look... at... me.
还是下次吧
Maybe next time.